# This file should contain all the record creation needed to seed the database with its default values.
# The data can then be loaded with the rails db:seed command (or created alongside the database with db:setup).
#
# Examples:
#
#   movies = Movie.create([{ name: 'Star Wars' }, { name: 'Lord of the Rings' }])
#   Character.create(name: 'Luke', movie: movies.first)
Card.create([
    {front: "that", back: "que"},
    {front: "of, from", back: "de"},
    {front: "no", back: "no"},
    {front: "to", back: "a"},
    {front: "the (for singular feminine nouns)", back: "la"},
    {front: "the (for singular masculine nouns)", back: "el"},
    {front: "he is, she is, it is (permanent characteristics)", back: "es"},
    {front: "and", back: "y"},
    {front: "in, on, at", back: "en"},
    {front: "it, him (direct object pronoun)", back: "lo"},
#     {front: "a, an (for singular masculine nouns)", back: "un"},
#     {front: "for, by, through", back: "por"},
#     {front: "what / how (as in “how nice!”)", back: "qué"},
#     {front: "me, myself", back: "me"},
#     {front: "a, an (for singular feminine nouns)", back: "una"},
#     {front: "you (direct-object pronoun)", back: "te"},
#     {front: "the (for plural masculine nouns)" , back: "los"},
#     {front: "himself, herself, itself", back: "se"},
#     {front: "with", back: "con"},
#     {front: "for, to", back: "para"},
#     {front: "my", back: "mi"},
#     {front: "he is, she is, it is (non-permanent characteristics)", back: "está"},
#     {front: "if", back: "si"},
#     {front: "well, good", back: "bien"},
#     {front: "but", back: "pero"},
#     {front: "I", back: "yo"},
#     {front: "that", back: "eso"},
#     {front: "the (for plural feminine nouns)", back: "las"},
#     {front: "yes", back: "sí"},
#     {front: "his, her, its", back: "su"},
#     {front: "your", back: "tu"},
#     {front: "here", back: "aquí"},
#     {front: "of the, from the, in the", back: "del"},
#     {front: "to the", back: "al"},
#     {front: "how, as, like", back: "como"},
#     {front: "him, her, formal you (indirect object pronoun)", back: "le"},
#     {front: "more", back: "más"},
#     {front: "this (for singular masculine nouns)", back: "esto"},
#     {front: "already", back: "ya"},
#     {front: "everything", back: "todo"},
#     {front: "this one (for singular feminine nouns)", back: "esta"},
#     {front: "let’s go, come on", back: "vamos"},
#     {front: "very", back: "muy"},
#     {front: "there is", back: "hay"},
#     {front: "now", back: "ahora"},
#     {front: "something", back: "algo"},
#     {front: "I am (nonpermanent characteristics)", back: "estoy"},
#     {front: "I have", back: "tengo"},
#     {front: "us", back: "nos"},
#     {front: "you", back: "tú"},
#     {front: "nothing", back: "nada"},
#     {front: "when", back: "cuando"},
#     {front: "he has, she has, it has (auxiliary verb)", back: "ha"},
#     {front: "this one (for singular masculine nouns)", back: "este"},
#     {front: "I know", back: "sé"},
#     {front: "you are (nonpermanent characteristics)", back: "estás"},
#     {front: "like this", back: "así"},
#     {front: "I can", back: "puedo"},
#     {front: "how", back: "cómo"},
#     {front: "I want", back: "quiero"},
#     {front: "only, just", back: "sólo"},
#     {front: "I am (permanent characteristics)", back: "soy"},
#     {front: "he has, she has, it has", back: "tiene"},
#     {front: "thank you", back: "gracias"},
#     {front: "or", back: "o"},
#     {front: "he", back: "él"},
#     {front: "good", back: "bueno"},
#     {front: "he was, she was, it was", back: "fue"},
#     {front: "to be (for permanent characteristics)", back: "ser"},
#     {front: "to do, to make", back: "hacer"},
#     {front: "they are (for permanent characteristics)", back: "son"},
#     {front: "all of us, all of them", back: "todos"},
#     {front: "he was, she was, it was (permanent characteristics)", back: "era"},
#     {front: "you are (permanent characteristics)", back: "eres"},
#     {front: "time (as in “one time”)", back: "vez"},
#     {front: "you have", back: "tienes"},
#     {front: "I believe", back: "creo"},
#     {front: "she", back: "ella"},
#     {front: "I have (auxiliary)", back: "he"},
#     {front: "that one", back: "ese"},
#     {front: "I go", back: "voy"},
#     {front: "he can, she can, it can", back: "puede"},
#     {front: "you know", back: "sabes"},
#     {front: "hello", back: "hola"},
#     {front: "his, her, its (for plural nouns)", back: "sus"},
#     {front: "because", back: "porque"},
#     {front: "God", back: "Dios"},
#     {front: "who", back: "quién"},
#     {front: "never", back: "nunca"},
#     {front: "where", back: "dónde"},
#     {front: "you want", back: "quieres"},
#     {front: "house", back: "casa"},
#     {front: "favor", back: "favor"},
#     {front: "that one (for singular feminine nouns)", back: "esa"},
#     {front: "two", back: "dos"},
#     {front: "so", back: "tan"},
#     {front: "mister, sir", back: "señor"},
#     {front: "time", back: "tiempo"},
#     {front: "truth", back: "verdad"},
#     {front: "I was (nonpermanent characteristics)", back: "estaba"},
])